<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BK1603</title>
    <link>https://bk1603.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on BK1603</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 13:43:09 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bk1603.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Code analysis</title>
      <link>https://bk1603.github.io/posts/dynamic_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 13:43:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bk1603.github.io/posts/dynamic_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with code debugging, we all know what code debugging is. We write some code, and then we check for errors (or bugs) in the code and try to fix them or remove them. We want to find and fix these bugs as early in the development process as posssible, because of a well known principle that states that fixing bugs later in the stages of development/release costs more than what it would in the earlier stages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to connect to JIIT Study Material</title>
      <link>https://bk1603.github.io/posts/how_to_study_material/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 13:31:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bk1603.github.io/posts/how_to_study_material/</guid>
      <description>I recently received a call from my room mate. He asked me about how he could access the &amp;ldquo;Study Material&amp;rdquo; shared folder from our college, mentioning that the college had sent us a file with directions for setting it up, (which I was blissfully unaware of, honestly I couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less about the classes starting right now :/)
Well, upon opening the file I did find some instructions, BUT they are only for windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Blog</title>
      <link>https://bk1603.github.io/posts/first-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 20:59:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bk1603.github.io/posts/first-blog/</guid>
      <description>What is this blog for? I&amp;rsquo;ll use this blog for writing about my adventures in open source. The issues that I fixed and how I fixed them. I might also write about how various open source softwares work &amp;ldquo;under the hood&amp;rdquo;. You know the good stuff ;)
I&amp;rsquo;ll try and write about any security vulnerabilities that I might find in open source softwares. Although this is a long shot, but well, if I do find something, I might as well write about how I found it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fd: The first problem at pwnable.kr</title>
      <link>https://bk1603.github.io/posts/fd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 17:31:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bk1603.github.io/posts/fd/</guid>
      <description>A word before we start Before starting the discussion of the problem, for anyone following these blog posts, I&amp;rsquo;d like to mention that everything required by these challenges can be read as and when necessary, but having a very basic knowledge of the linux command line, file permission bits on linux and tools like ssh, scp and nc would be very helpful. Also try reading the man pages of any command line tool the use of which you couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://bk1603.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 16:39:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bk1603.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! I&amp;rsquo;m Shreyansh, glad to have you on board. I am a college student pursuing bachelors of technology in computer science. I&amp;rsquo;d like to describe myself as curious. I like to know how things work under the hood. I find that contributing to open source projects really helps me with that. I am a contributor to various open source organisations. You can checkout my github profile for more info! My username, as you might have guessed is BK1603.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
